<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>martin</title>
    <link>https://romazzino.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on martin</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://romazzino.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>eSk8</title>
      <link>https://romazzino.github.io/projects/esk8/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://romazzino.github.io/projects/esk8/</guid>
      <description>topology optimization
this is a frame design for an electric skateboard that has been topology optimized to reduce weight and improve stiffness while offering enough space internally to house the electrical components and battery. the plugin used was t0pos. inputs to the model are applied forces, bearings and raw build volume. the system is cfd analised and material removed where the stress is least. results vary depending on resolution of voxels.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>mineral structure gridshell</title>
      <link>https://romazzino.github.io/projects/studio2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://romazzino.github.io/projects/studio2/</guid>
      <description>a shell structure that derives its geometry from the mineral herbertsmithite, which has a hexagonaly ordered arrangement of atoms. This geometry, transferred to a supporting structure, offers advantages for the load-bearing capacity and thus the lightness of the structure.
This system consists of two repetitive standardized parts, a triangle and an octahedron, which are connected with stiff nodes that are unique for each position in the shell.
the parametric model for this project covers topics such as vector optimization, stress testing, sun analysis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>prefab_concrete</title>
      <link>https://romazzino.github.io/projects/studio_one/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://romazzino.github.io/projects/studio_one/</guid>
      <description>The system rombo is a modular structure consisting of 3D-printed concrete shells that are easy to stack and transport. These elements are placed on site, reinforced and then cast with in-situ concrete to form a solid beam grid.
the elements are fully configurable via grasshopper as well as the grid layout and shape of the quadripartite columns.
catalog gh_def</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>prototyping</title>
      <link>https://romazzino.github.io/projects/3d_print/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://romazzino.github.io/projects/3d_print/</guid>
      <description>3dprint / digital fab
digital fabrication has accompanied me for a few years now. I have been in charge of the lasercutting @ intitute of architecture and media. This has evolved in the development of prototypes, like the cylinder head for a racing motor bike as seen below. digital fabrication like cnc milling, lasercutting and 3d printing are one of my passions and hobbies.
milling_vid</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>expo_pavillion</title>
      <link>https://romazzino.github.io/projects/pavillion/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://romazzino.github.io/projects/pavillion/</guid>
      <description>lightweight adaptive structure
As part of a team of three we developed an adaptive structure pavillion My contribution to the project was the 3d_geometry development, parametrization and simulation of the structure as well as the development of the movement. The project took part in the international IASS-competition in barcelona and has been awarded first prize.
3dm_file brochure</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>drone_mapping</title>
      <link>https://romazzino.github.io/projects/drone_mapping/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://romazzino.github.io/projects/drone_mapping/</guid>
      <description>I have been flying drones and helicopters for many years, racing FPV drones and drone mapping of terrain and buildings for 3d reconstruction. The mapping is based on photogrammetry and not lidar based. I am used to work on big point clouds &amp;gt;5gb. My racing drones are built by myself although for reconstruction purposes commercial drones are used.
mapping_mesh1 mapping_mesh2</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://romazzino.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2016 21:05:33 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://romazzino.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>about me :)</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
